Guide to the Lee Emerson Bassett Toastmasters Club (Stanford University) Records SC0244
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Lee Emerson Bassett Toastmasters Club (Stanford University) records
1974-1986
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Lee Emerson Bassett Toastmasters Club (Stanford University)
SC0244
1.25 Linear Feet
Files include "A History of the Lee Emerson Bassett Toastmasters Club" by Shahid Mutjaba and Dianne Goldbach, 1980; the weekly bulletin "The Orator" 1974-1980, which includes minutes of their meetings; and VHS tapes of meetings from 1983-1986.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Administrative transfer, Lee Emerson Bassett Club, 1981 adn 2008.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
The club was first organized in 1934 by Dr. Virgil Anderson and officially chartered by the Toastmasters International in May 1935. Lee Emerson Bassett became the instructor of the club soon after it was chartered and was involved until his death in 1959. The club was renamed the Emerson Lee Bassett Toastmasters Club in his honor..
Description of the Collection
Files include "A History of the Lee Emerson Bassett Toastmasters Club" by Shahid Mutjaba and Dianne Goldbach, 1980; the weekly bulletin "The Orator" 1974-1980, which includes minutes of their meetings; and VHS tapes of meetings from 1983-1986.
Universities and colleges -- Societies, etc.; Lee Emerson Bassett Toastmasters Club (Stanford University); Stanford University; Lee Emerson Bassett Toastmasters Club (Stanford University)
- Records
  - A History ofthe Lee Emerson Basset Toastmaster's Club (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - The Orator masters for 1980 issues (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - The Orator weekly bulletin, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Orator weekly bulletin, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - The Orator weekly bulletin, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - The Orator weekly bulletin, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - The Orator weekly bulletin, 1976 Mar.-Dec. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - The Orator weekly bulletin, 1974-75 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - LEB #1 1983 -2-9 to 3-23, 244.1; 1 videotape(s) (vhs) (Box 2)
  - LEB #2 1983 -3-23 to 4-6, 244.2; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - LEB #3 1983 -4-13 to 5-4, 244.3 (Box 2)
  - LEB #4 1983 -5-25 to 6-22, 244.4 (Box 2)
  - LEB #5 [1983] -6-22, 244.5 (Box 2)
  - LEB #7 1983 -8-24 to 10-19, 244.6 (Box 2)
  - LEB #8 -[no other details on label], 244.7 (Box 2)
  - LEB #9 -[no other details on label], 244.8 (Box 2)
  - LEB #10 [no year noted] -3-21, 244.9; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 2)
  - LEB #11 1984 -4-25 to 6-13, 244.10 (Box 2)
  - [unnumbered] End 5-8-85, 244.11; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - LEB#171985-5-15t06-19, 244.12 (Box 3)
  - LEB #18 1985 -6-19 to 7-17, 244.13 (Box 3)
  - LEB#181985-7-17t08-14, 244.14 (Box 3)
  - [unnumbered] 1985 -10-16 to 11-13, 244.15 (Box 3)
  - [unnumbered] 1985-1986 -12/4/85 to 11/22/86, 244.16 (Box 3)
  - [unnumbered] 1986 -1/29 to 2/19, 244.17; 1 videotape(s) (VHS) (Box 3)
  - 2 unlabeled, unmarked tapes and 1 tape labeled "Johnny Carson's last week" (Box 3)